DUNKIRK
敦刻爾克
THE ENEMY HAVE DRIVEN THE BRITISH AND FRENCH ARMIES TO THE SEA
受敵方壓制 英法聯軍撤至海邊
"WE SURROUND YOU"
"你們已被包圍"
TRAPPED AT DUNKIRK, THEY AWAIT THEIR FATE
困於敦刻爾克 等候命運降臨
HOPING FOR DELIVERANCE
祈求奇跡出現
FOR A MIRACLE
以逃出重圍
English! I'm English!
英國人! 我是英國人! 英國人!
Allez, Anglais. Bon voyage.
走吧 英國佬 快溜吧
It's grenadiers, mate.
這堿O擲彈兵團 夥計
Make way!
讓開
Out of the way!
Go, go, go!
走走走
Along the mole. All the way.
沿著防波堤 一路走過去
The ship's about to leave.
船就要開
Along the mole. All the way. The ship's about to leave.
沿著防波堤 一路走過去 船就要開了
1. THE MOLE one week
陸 一周
Where's the bloody air force?
我們的空軍都死哪去了?!
2. THE SEA one day
海 一天
The navy's requisitioned her.
海軍要徵用這船
They'll be back in an hour. My dad wants to be ready before then.
他們一小時內回來 父親想在那之前準備妥當
They've told us to strip her and load those life jackets.
海軍要我們清理船艙 給救生衣騰地方
Some men across the Channel, at Dunkirk, need taking off.
有些人在對岸的敦刻爾克 他們需要這船
Some men?
有些人?
3. THE AIR one hour
空 一小時
Check fuel, Fortis 1 and 2.
檢查燃油 福蒂斯小隊1號 2號
70 gallons.
70加侖(318升)
68 gallons, Fortis Leader.
68加侖(309升) 福蒂斯長機
Stay down at 500 feet to leave fuel
高度降至500英尺(152米) 節省燃料
for 40-minute fighting time over Dunkirk.
準備在敦刻爾克上空戰鬥40分鐘
Understood. Vector 128, angels point five.
明白 航向128 高度500英尺(152米)
And keep an eye on that gauge, even when it gets lively.
隨時注意儀表讀數
Save enough to get back.
預留充足返航燃料
No French soldiers. No French soldiers. No.
不收法軍 不收法軍
No, no French. English only. English only past this point.
不不 不收法國人 只向英國人開放 只收英軍!
No. It's a British ship. No, you have your own ships.
不 這艘是英國船 你們會有自己的
Get back. Get back.
退後! 退後!
No, you've got your own ships. This is a British ship.
你們的船會到的 這是英國船
No, get back.
退後!
Look, get the stretchers through. There are stretchers coming.
把擔架抬過來 有擔架來了
Get out of the way! Out of the way!
讓開來! 別擋道!
Go, go, go. Along the mole. All the way.
沿著防波堤 一路走過去
The ship's about to leave. About to leave.
船快要開了 快開了
Along the mole. All the way.
沿著防波堤 一路走過去
Along the mole. Along the mole. All the way. All the way.
沿著防波堤 一路過去
No.
不行
No, English only. English only!
只收英國人! 只收英國人!
No!
不行
Ready on the stern!
船艉已就緒!
Yes, sir!
是 長官
Man the bowline!
升起船帆!
Any more room?
還有位置嗎?
You have to get back!
退回去! 退回去!
That's two minutes.
只剩兩分鐘
You've missed it. You've missed it.
你們已經錯過了 錯過了
Is that the last one?
這是最後一個了嗎?
Aye, sir.
是 長官
Break the line.
解掉船纜!
Come on! Come on!
出發! 出發!
Dunkirk's so far. Why can't they just load at Calais?
敦刻爾克太遠了 怎麼不到加來(法國)上船?
The enemy had something to say about it.
敵人可不答應
Ah, down here we're sitting ducks.
從這出發 他們可就成活靶子了
Keep 'em peeled. They'll come out of the sun.
保持警惕 敵機會在太陽方位出現
Up the line.
排隊
Oi. We'll take it.
嘿 交給我們 ...
Drop the gangplank!
收起跳板!
Yes, sir!
是 長官
Take a run at it.
試著走過來!
Ready on the stern line, George.
把艉纜收好 喬治
Aren't you waiting on the navy?
不等海軍的人了嗎?
They've asked for the Moonstone, they'll have her.
他們要徵用"月光寶石"號 那就給他們吧
And her captain.
船長跟著船走
And his son.
他兒子也去
Thanks for the help, George.
謝謝你來幫忙 喬治
What are you doing?
你在幹嘛?
You do know where we're going?
你知道我們去哪嗎?
France.
去法國
Into war, George.
是去參戰 喬治
I'll be useful, sir.
我會幫上忙的 先生
Bandit, 11 o'clock.
敵機 8點鐘方向
Break.
散開
He's on me.
他咬住我了
I'm on him.
我對付他
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8...
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight...
Oi, you two.
你倆 趕緊回去!
Get a shift on.
上岸歸隊!
Yeah, pull him tight. Tie a knot in it.
把這拉緊了 打個結
Back up the line. Both of you.
你們兩個 退後
Off you go.
可以走了!
Off you go!
That last barrage has damaged the rudder.
上次轟炸把船舵給弄壞了!
Uh, okay...
呃 ... 好的
Mr. Dawson!
道森先生!
One of ours, George.
咱們的飛機 喬治
On my mark, Fortis 2. Draw him left.
福蒂斯2號 聽我口令 誘他到左舷
3, 2, 1
Three, two, one.
Mark.
機動
Clear.
搞定
Is he down?
他墜機了嗎?
Yeah, he's down for the count.
對 他完蛋了
Fortis Leader, one bandit down.
福蒂斯長機 擊落敵機一架
Fortis Leader, do you read?
福蒂斯長機 收到了嗎?
Fortis 2, I have you to my port. I have no eyes on Fortis Leader. Over.
福蒂斯2號 你在我左舷 但我看不到長機 完畢
Understood, Fortis 1.
明白 福蒂斯1號
Orbit for a look.
繞圈搜尋 ...
How long, Lieutenant?
還要多久 上尉?
We need to run a new cable, sir. They're scrambling.
得換新纜繩 長官 舊的纏得厲害
Very well.
去吧
Colonel, you're gonna have to decide how many more wounded to evacuate.
上校 你得下決定了 還要撤離多少傷員 ...
One stretcher takes the space of seven standing men.
一副擔架就得擠掉7個人的位置
Excuse me.
對不起
- Rear Admiral. - Commander.
- 少將 - 中校
How's the perimeter?
防線如何?
Shrinking every day.
每天都在收縮
But between our rear guard and the French, we're holding the line.
不過後衛部隊和法軍 都還在堅守陣地
And the enemy tanks have stopped.
還有 敵人的坦克停下來了
Why have they stopped?
為什麼?
Waste precious tanks
光靠空襲就夠了 咱們已經是甕中之鱉
when they can pick us off from the air, like fish in a barrel?
何必再耗費寶貴的坦克?
How long does London expect the army to hold out before we make terms?
在達成協議前 倫敦方面 還要我們守多久?
Make terms?
達成協議?
They're not stopping here. We need to get our army back.
德國人不會善罷甘休的 我們得把軍隊撤回去
Britain's next and then the rest of the world.
敵人下一步就是英國 然後就是稱霸世界
Christ.
老天 ...
I mean, you can practically see it from here.
在這幾乎都能望見了 ...
What?
什麼?
Home.
家
What about the French?
法國人怎麼辦?
Publicly, Churchill's told them, "Bras dessous."
檯面上 丘吉爾說要"手挽著手"
Arm in arm, leaving together.
攜手並肩 不離不棄
And privately?
私下呢？
We need our army back.
讓咱們的人撤回來
How many men are they talking about, sir?
要撤多少人 長官?
Churchill wants 30,000. Ramsay's hoping we can give him 45.
丘吉爾的計劃是3萬人 拉姆齊中將希望能撤4萬5千人
There are 400,000 men on this beach, sir.
這海灘上可擠了40萬人 長官
We'll just have to do our best.
大家都盡力吧
Right, well, this mole stays open at all costs.
沒錯 要不惜一切代價 讓防波堤保持暢通
We're in artillery range from the west. If anything else sinks here,
我們處在西側敵人的炮火範圍內 要是這兒有東西沉了
the mole's blocked and we're stuffed.
就會堵癱整個防波堤
Can't we load from the beaches?
不能到海灘上裝船嗎?
Better than standing out here when the dive bombs come.
總比呆這兒挨炸要強
- It's impossible. - Too shallow?
- 不可能的 - 水太淺嗎?
'Cause anything that drafts over three feet can't get near.
吃水超過3英尺(0.9米) 船就進不來
We don't have enough small boats to ferry men to the destroyers.
我們的划槳船也不夠 沒法把人分批送上驅逐艦
The mole it is, then, gentlemen.
那麼先生們 全靠防波堤了
Hey!
嘿
Hey! Can you swim it?
嘿! 你能游過來嗎?
Dad, can you get closer?
能不能再近點?
Can't risk it!
別冒險!
Hang on.
堅持住
What's your name?
你叫什麼名字?
Wreckage below.
下面有殘骸
Is it more of the 109?
109戰機嗎?
No.
不
It's Fortis Leader. Over.
是福蒂斯長機 完畢
You think he got out?
他逃出來沒?
I didn't see a 'chute.
我沒見到降落傘
Record his position.
記錄長機坐標
Then set heading 128,
轉至128航向 高度 ...
height 1,000. Over.
1000英尺(305米) 完畢
Vector 128, angels one. Understood.
航向128 高度1000英尺(305米) 明白
Fortis 2, what's your fuel?
福蒂斯2號 燃油狀況?
50 gallons. Over.
50加侖(189升) 完畢
50 gallons.
50加侖(189升)
All right, keep letting me know.
好的 保持提醒
My gauge took a bit of a knock back there.
我的儀表剛才被打壞了
Shouldn't you turn back?
你要不要返航?
No, no.
不用
I'm fairly confident it's just the gauge.
相信只是儀表出了問題
- She's going down! - Cut her loose!
- 船要沉了! - 砍掉纜繩!
What about the wounded?
傷員們怎麼辦?
Abandon ship! Abandon ship!
全體棄船 棄船!
Cut her loose, and push her off!
砍掉纜繩 把船挪走!
We can't let her sink at the mole!
別讓船沉在這兒!
Push the bloody boat off!
推下去!
Help us!
救命!
Do you want to come below?
你要不要下來?
It's much warmer.
媕Y更暖和
It's out of the wind.
甲板上風大
Here you go.
喝點吧
Leave him be, George.
別管他 喬治
He feels safer on deck.
呆在甲板上 他覺得更安全
You would too if you'd been bombed.
你被炸了也會有同感
U-boat.
U型潛艇
It was a U-boat.
是U型潛艇
Get him some more tea, George.
再給他倒杯茶 喬治
Right, we're about five minutes out,
好了 我們還有5分鐘航程
so climb to 2,000. Over.
爬升至2000英尺(610米) 完畢
That's more fuel.
那樣更費油吧
I know, but I don't want to get jumped again.
現在我可不想遭遇敵機
Let's get a decent altitude.
咱們先爬升上去
We can dive down on the bastards from above. Over.
然後再俯衝作戰 完畢
Understood. Angels two.
明白 二號
Over.
完畢
Right, Highlanders.
好了 高地兵
Let's find you another ship.
再給你們找艘船吧
Come on.
快點
Everyone else, keep climbing. Climb on the deck.
所有人 繼續爬 爬到甲板上
Climb on the deck.
爬到甲板上
Watch your heads on the rail. Watch it.
小心! 小心別碰到頭了!
That's right, keep going down. Take a blanket.
往下走 拿上毯子
Down you go. Put this on, my love.
從這兒往下走 披上這個 親愛的
Down you go. Keep going down.
往下走 一直往下走
There's a nice cup of tea for you down there.
底下給你們準備了熱茶
Keep moving down.
一直往下走
Take a blanket.
裹上毯子
Try and make some room.
好了 挪一挪
Keep moving down, boys.
往下走 小伙子們
This way.
走這邊
A cup of tea down there.
這埵陳虪i供飲用
There you go. Down there. Move down there.
這邊 請往下走!
What's wrong with your friend?
你朋友怎麼了?
He's looking for a quick way out.
他在找逃生捷徑
In case we go down.
萬一船沉了 就派上用場了
Where are we going?
我們要去哪兒?
Dunkirk.
敦刻爾克
No, uh, no, no, we're going to England.
不 不 我知道 是回英格蘭!
We have to go to Dunkirk first.
我們得先去敦刻爾克
Look, I'm not going back.
我不要回去!
I'm not going back.
我不要回去 ...
Look at it.
你瞧瞧!
If we go there, we'll die.
如果我們 ... 我們去了就死定了!
I see your point, son.
我明白你的意思了 年輕人
Well, let's plot a course.
咱們繪個航線吧
You can take your tea below and warm up.
你先下去喝喝茶 暖暖身子
Peter, have we got space for a man to lie down?
彼得 給他找個地方休息下
Uh, yeah.
好的
Here, come on.
這 來吧
Careful.
小心
Just in there.
就這
I'll get you some more tea.
我去給你加點茶
Is he a coward, Mr. Dawson?
他是懦夫嗎 道森先生?
He's shell-shocked, George.
喬治 他患了炮彈休克癥
He's not himself.
現在神志不清
He may never be himself again.
搞不好一輩子都這樣了
Here you are.
喝吧
40 gallons, Fortis 1.
40加侖(151升) 福蒂斯1號
40 gallons, understood.
40加侖(151升) 明白
Heinkel, 11 o'clock.
海因克爾轟炸機 11點鐘方向
She's lining up to drop her load on that minesweeper.
它在轟炸隊形 目標是掃雷艦
Fighters?
戰鬥機呢?
Yeah, 109s off her starboard.
恩 都是109 在它右舷
I'm on the bomber.
我負責轟炸機
Got him! Got him!
打中了! 打中了!
Oh, she's turning. You must've damaged her.
它轉向了 肯定被你擊中了
Where's the escort?
護衛機呢?
Well, I got one of...
我擊落一架 ...
Jesus!
噢! 上帝!
I'm going down.
我正在下墜
I'm on him. Bail out.
我纏住他 你跳傘
No, the swell looks good. I'm ditching.
海況良好 準備水上迫降
Don't leave us!
別拋下我們
Come back!
回來!
- Wait for us! - Help! Help us!
- 等等我們! - 救命!
Pick us up! Pick us up!
帶我們走! 帶我們走!
Come back!
回來!
Torpedo!
魚雷!
Abandon ship! Abandon ship!
棄船!
Help!
救命!
Get us out of here!
把我們救出去!
Spitfires, George.
噴火戰鬥機 喬治
Greatest plane ever built.
史上最棒的飛機
You didn't even look.
你沒看就知道啦
Rolls-Royce Merlin engines.
勞斯萊斯「梅林」發動機
Sweetest sound you could hear out here.
這是戰場上最悅耳的聲音了
Hello?
有人嗎?!
Could you open the door?
把門打開!
Hello? Can you hear me?
喂 能聽到我嗎?
Open the door!
快開門哪!
Do you hear me?
能聽見我嗎?!
He wants to come out.
他想出來
What have you done? Locked him in?
你幹了什麼? 把他鎖媕Y?
Let him out, for God's sake.
讓他出來 天吶!
Hello?
有人嗎?
Let me out!
讓我出去!
You haven't turned around.
你們沒有掉頭!
No. We have a job to do.
沒有 我們有任務在身
Job? This is a pleasure yacht.
任 ... 任務? 這 ... 這可是艘遊艇!
You're weekend sailors, not the bloody navy.
你們 ... 你們只是業餘水手 又不是海軍!
A man your age?
像你這把年紀的人 …
Men my age dictate this war.
像我這把年紀的人 有些正在主導這場戰爭
Why should we be allowed to send our children to fight it?
我們又憑什麼 只讓年輕人去戰鬥?
You should be at home!
你就該待家媕Y!
Well, there won't be any home if we allow a slaughter across the Channel.
如果這場戰爭蔓延到英國 我也就無家可歸了
He's turning tail. I'm gonna get after him.
他掉頭逃了 我去追他
Good luck.
祝好運
Watch your fuel. You're at 15 gallons.
留意燃油 你還有15加侖(57升)
15 gallons, understood.
15加侖(57升) 明白
Best of luck, Collins.
祝你好運 柯林斯
Collins, do you read?
柯林斯 你沒事吧?
Oi! No! No!
不! 不!
Get off! Get off!
一邊去!
Piss off, the both of you. It's too crowded.
滾開 船上太擠了!
You can't leave us!
你們不能撇下我們!
Make some room!
騰騰位子!
No!
不! 不!
No! Get off!
一邊去!
You men, leave off. You'll capsize the boat.
你們快住手 船會翻掉的
She's gone over twice on the way out here.
來這的路上已經翻過兩次了
You have to stay calm. There are plenty of boats.
冷靜下來 船是夠用的
Calm?
冷靜?!
Wait till you get torpedoed, then tell us to be calm!
等你也被魚雷炸了 再來扯這個吧!
You have life jackets?
你們有救生衣嗎?
Yes, they do.
有 他們有的
Don't panic, boys. The water's not too rough
你們不要慌 海水還算平靜
or too cold.
也不太冷
We're heading back to the beach.
我們先回海灘上
- Let's go to Dover! - Yeah!
- 咱們去多佛(英國)吧! - 對!
We can't make it across the Channel in this, lads.
這船沒法渡過海峽 夥計們
We need to get back to the beach and wait for another ride.
我們得回到海灘上 等下一班船
You men in the water, float here, save your strength.
水堛漣怚S們 保持體力
We'll come back for you.
我們會回來接你們的
Oars in!
提槳!
Together, pull!
提槳! 劃!
提! 劃!
Pull!
劃!
Together, pull!
提槳! 劃!
Pull!
劃!
Together, pull!
提! 劃!
There's no hiding from this, son.
這是躲不掉的 孩子
What is it you think you can do out there, on this thing?
你以為你們能幫到什麼?  就憑這玩意?
There's not just us. A call went out.
我們不是孤軍作戰 號令下來了
We aren't the only ones to answer, you know.
大家都挺身而出
You don't even have guns.
你們連槍都沒有!
Do you have a gun?
你有槍嗎?
Yes, of course. A rifle, a 303.
有 當然了! 來復步槍 303口徑
Did it help you against the dive bombers and the U-boats?
它能幫你回擊俯衝轟炸機嗎? U型潛艇呢?
You're an old fool.
你真是個老糊塗
I'm not going back.
我不會回去的!
不會回去的!
Turn it around.
掉頭返航!
I'm not turning round.
我們不會掉頭的
Turn it around!
掉回去!
Turn it...
讓它掉 ...
- Calm it down, mate. - Turn it around!
- 冷靜 老兄! - 掉頭回去
Wait, wait!
冷靜 冷靜
Calm it down, mate.
冷靜點 老兄!
George?
喬治?
George!
喬治?!
What have you done?
你都做了什麼?
Okay, you're all right, George.
好的 你沒事了 喬治
You're all right.
你沒事的!
Hang on. Okay. Okay, just...
堅持住
That's it. That's good enough.
好的 現在
It's gonna keep some pressure on. There we go.
要給你壓一下 好了
There we go.
好了
Can you hear me, George?
能聽到我嗎 喬治?
Come on, lads!
加把勁 夥計們
Come on! Come on, boys!
It's a pier.
等到海水漲起來
For when the water comes in.
就把它當碼頭用
The tide's turning now.
現在在漲潮了
How can you tell?
你怎麼知道?
The bodies come back.
屍體都漂回來了
Hey.
嘿!
Hey, Highlanders!
嘿! 高地兵們!
What's that way?
那邊是什麼?
A boat.
有艘船
She's grounded.
擱淺了
Not when the tide comes in, she's not.
等到漲潮後 就不是了
Be a brave lad.
挺住 兄弟
You and Mr. Dawson?
遇見你和道森先生
It's the best thing I've ever done.
是我做過最棒的事情
You're all right. You're okay.
你沒事的 你很好
Sea Cadet. It's the only thing I've ever done.
參加海事青年團 那是我做過的唯一一件事了
It's all right. It's okay. Just have some water.
沒事的 好了 喝口水吧
I told my dad...
我跟父親說過
I've done nothing at school
我在學校媮鷁M一事無成
and that I would do something one day.
可總有一天會混出點名堂
Maybe get in the local paper.
也許會登上本地報紙
Maybe my teachers would see it.
也許老師們會讀到我的報道
Okay, get some rest.
好了 休息一下
I need you back up on deck as soon as you're able.
等你恢復了 甲板上我還需要你
I can't.
做不到
What?
什麼?
I can't see.
我看不見了
Sir.
長官
The French have been forced back on the western side.
西側的法軍已經被迫後撤了
They're still holding a perimeter?
但原來的防線還在吧?
For now.
目前是的
Officer coming through. Move yourselves. Move yourselves!
給長官讓路 都讓讓 讓讓!
Where are the destroyers?
驅逐艦在哪?
There'll be one soon.
很快會再來一艘
One?
一艘?
After yesterday's losses, it's one ship on the mole at a time.
經過昨天的損失 現在一次就來一艘了
The battle is here.
這就是戰場
What the hell are they saving them for?
他們藏著船究竟想做什麼?
The next battle.
為了以後的戰鬥
The one for Britain.
為了保衛不列顛
It's the same with the planes.
飛機也一樣
But it's right there.
可英國近在眼前!
You can practically...
你幾乎可以看 ...
Seeing home doesn't help us get there, Colonel.
就算看得到 也不意味著你能平安返家 上尉
They need to send more ships.
那邊得增派更多船隻
Every hour the enemy pushes closer.
敵人時刻都在逼近
They've activated the small vessels pool.
當局已經啟用"小型運力池"來增援了
Small vessels?
"小型運力"
It's the list of civilian boats for requisition.
也就是徵召民船
Civilian?
民船?
We need destroyers.
我們要的是驅逐艦
Small boats can load from the beach.
小船可以到海灘上載人
Not in these conditions.
但現在不合適
Well, I'd rather face waves than dive bombers.
比起俯衝轟炸 我寧願它波浪滔天
No, you're right. They won't get up in this.
說的沒錯 這海況沒法出航 ...
The Royal Engineers are building piers from lorries.
皇家工兵團在用卡車搭建臨時碼頭
At least that should help us when the tide comes back.
起碼在漲潮後能派上用場
Well, we'll know in six hours' time.
我們只有6個小時
I thought the tides were every three?
不是3小時一次漲潮嗎?
Then it's good that you're army and I'm navy, isn't it?
所以才說 你是陸軍 我是海軍 對吧?
There. Vanquisher.
那兒 "征服者"號驅逐艦 ...
Where's the crew?
船員去哪兒了?
Probably got spooked after they ran aground.
可能是擱淺後害怕了
Scarpered up the beach.
逃到了海灘上
Why?
為什麼?
'Cause we're outside the perimeter. Enemy could be right there.
因為我們在防線外頭 敵人可能就在附近
All right, best shut ourselves inside, boys.
好的 咱們最好藏到媕Y 弟兄們!
Wait for the high tide.
然後待到漲潮
How long's that?
那要多久?
Every three hours.
3小時一次
I've put a bit of pressure on it.
我用力壓住了傷口
Strapped him up, made him comfortable.
給他纏上了繃帶 希望能他能舒服些
What?
什麼?
It's bad, Dad.
他情況很糟 爸爸
Well, should we turn back?
我們要不要掉頭?
We've come so far.
船都到這了
Dad, is that one of ours?
那邊是咱們的飛機嗎?
That's a Heinkel. They'll go for that minesweeper there.
那架是海因克爾轟炸機 他們要攻擊那艘掃雷艦
Hang on. Shouldn't we stand by to pick up survivors?
我們是不是要準備援救倖存者了?
To do that we have to survive ourselves.
先活下來再說吧
Poke your head out. See if the water's come in.
把頭伸出去 看看漲潮了沒
Talkative sod, aren't you?
你不是很健談麼?
It's barely come in at all.
幾乎沒有
- Fuck's sake. - Calm down.
- 他媽的! - 冷靜點!
What goes out comes back in again, right?
有退潮自然會有漲潮 不是麼?
Yeah, but how long?
對啊 但要等多久?
Spitfires!
噴火戰鬥機!
Come on.
加油
Come on, come on.
加油 加油
Dad, he got him!
爸爸! 他打中了!
Yeah! Yeah!
好!
The Heinkel's moving off.
轟炸機飛走了!
Yeah.
對!
Oh, no.
噢 不
Smoke from the Spitfire!
那架噴火戰鬥機著火了!
Watch for a parachute!
注意降落傘的位置!
Are you German?
- 你是德國人?
No, Dutch. Dutch!
- 不 荷蘭人! 我是荷蘭人!
Merchant navy.
我是商船隊的
Here to pick you up. To help you.
- 來接你們 來幫忙的
Why'd you leave your boat?
- 幹嘛要離開船?
In case the Germans come.
我們擔心德國人會過來
We wait up the beach.
我們在海灘上
With the soldiers. Wait for the tide.
跟大家一起 等漲潮呢
You came back. The tide must be in.
你回來了 那肯定是漲潮了
Coming. Coming, yes.
對 漲了 ... 沒錯兒
But more hours till we float.
但還得再等幾個小時 船才能浮起來
Hours?
幾個小時!
Why'd you come back?
那怎麼現在就回來了?
Not so heavy when I left.
我走的時候船堨i沒這麼多人啊!
No 'chute!
沒有降落傘!
Best of luck, Collins.
祝你好運 柯林斯
Collins, do you read?
柯林斯 你還好嗎?
He's down.
飛機墜毀了
Dad.
爸
Dad, watch the engine.
爸 看那引擎
Dad, he's down. There was no 'chute.
他完蛋了 他沒有降落傘
Dad, come on. There was no 'chute.
爸 別去了 他沒降落傘
He's probably dead.
估計人已經死了
Damn it, I hear you, Peter! I hear you!
彼得 別說了 我聽到了
He may be alive. Maybe.
說不定還活著呢 誰說得準
We may be able to help him.
也許還能救他一命
No! Then they'll know we're in here.
別亂來! 我們會暴露的
Why else are they shooting at us?
除了咱們 他們還能射誰?!
Look at the grouping.
你們看那隊形
Target practice.
在練靶子而已
Go. Plug it. Go, go.
去 堵上它 快去
We have to plug it.
咱們得把洞堵上!
After you, mate.
那你先請吧!
You ready? Go!
怎麼離開這兒?!
How do we get off? Do we need to ditch some ballast?
我們得扔掉些壓艙物?!
Weight! Do we need to lose weight?
太重了! 我們要減輕重量!
Weight. Weight, yes.
減重 對
Yes.
沒錯
Somebody needs to get off.
我們要送個人出去
Well volunteered.
有人自願麼?
We don't need a volunteer.
不必這樣
I know someone who ought to get off.
我知道誰該出去 ...
This one.
就是他
He's a German spy.
他是德國間諜
Don't be daft.
別瞎說
He's a fucking Jerry.
他是德國鬼子
Have you noticed he hasn't said a word?
你們有沒有注意到他一直一言不發
'Cause I have.
我是注意到了
He don't speak English.
他根本就不會英語
If he does it's with an accent that's thicker than sauerkraut sauce.
就算會說 也帶著一股濃濃的德國泡菜味
You're daft. Tell him.
胡說八道 快回擊他
Yeah.
沒錯
Tell me.
儘管說吧
Tell me, Gibson.
說啊 吉布森!
Tell me!
說話!
Tell him, for God's sake!
我的天 說句話啊!
A frog.
青蛙佬
A bloody frog.
你個臭青蛙佬
A cowardly little queue-jumping frog.
插隊的懦夫
Who's Gibson, eh?
吉布森又是誰 嗯?
Some naked, dead Englishman lying out on that sand?
肯定是沙灘上某個裸死的英國人
Did you at least have the decency to bury him?
你扒完他的衣服 有沒有把人安葬好?
He did. I helped him. I thought it was his mate.
葬好了 我倆一塊埋的 我以為那是他的戰友
- Maybe he killed him. - He didn't kill him.
- 沒準兒就是他殺的吉布森呢 - 他沒殺那人
How do we know?
你又怎麼知道?!
How hard is it to find a dead Englishman on Dunkirk beach?
在這兒的海灘上找一具英國人屍體 能有多難?
He didn't kill anyone.
他沒殺人
He was just looking for a way off the sand, like the rest of us.
他跟咱們一樣 只想趕緊離開這鬼地方!
Haven't they had enough practice by now?
那邊槍還沒練夠嗎?!
They're trying to make sure she won't float.
他們在確保船沒法浮起來
Will she still float?
這船還能浮起來?!
Float, yes. Yes, with less weight.
浮起來 可以的 減輕重量就行了
And we know who's getting off.
最該趕誰出去 大家心堻ㄡM楚
No, you can't do that. He's French. He's on our side.
不能那樣 他是法國的盟友 自己人
Go on. Up you go.
好啊 那你走吧
As soon as he pokes his head out, they'll slaughter him.
你把他趕出去 他就死定了
Better him than me.
反正死的不是我
It's not fair.
這不公平
Survival's not fair.
保命要緊 扯啥公平
No, it's shit.
說得對
It's fear, and it's greed.
都怕死 都貪生
Fate pushed through the bowels of men.
那就以多服少
Shit.
媽的
He saved our lives.
他救過大家的命
And he's about to do it again.
那他馬上可以再救一次了!
No, don't! Stop!
不! 等一等!
Somebody's gotta get off, so the rest of us can live.
必須得讓個人下船 不然全都活不成
If you wanna volunteer...
你願不願意出去?
Fuck no.
沒門兒
I'm going home.
我要回家
And if this is the price?
如果這就是條件呢?
I'll live with it.
我可以接受
But it's wrong.
但這錯得離譜
Go on!
出去!
One man's not going to make enough difference.
就趕一個人出去 也沒多大用
You'd best hope it does, because you'd be volunteering next.
你最好希望這招有用 不然下一個就輪到你了
What?
什麼?
We're regimental brothers, mate.
夥計 大家都是戰友
It's just the way it is.
就該有犧牲自己的覺悟
We float!
浮起來了!
Start the bloody engine!
快啟動發動機!
Afternoon.
下午好
I'm sorry, son. I really don't know.
抱歉 朋友 我 ... 我真的不知道
You're right not moving him.
你做的對 不該挪動他
You've done the best for him you can.
你已經盡全力了
We've wasted the day.
我們白忙了一天
I share your frustration, Colonel.
我也很沮喪 上校
Johnny!
約翰尼!
Grounded trawler, taking fire.
那艘擱淺的拖網漁船著火了
They're breaking through the dunes to the east.
敵人從東側沙丘帶攻了過來
This is it.
守不住了
Plug the holes!
堵住彈孔!
With what?
用什麼堵
Plug the holes!
堵住彈孔!
Other side! Other side!
那邊 去那邊堵住
What do you see?
看到什麼了?
Home.
家
Is he all right? The boy?
他還好吧? 小伙?
No.
不
No, he's not.
他不好
Dad!
爸!
Come on. Come on, Farrier. Come on.
加油 加油
There's men in the water!
那邊有人在漂著
Oil.
油
It's oil. Oil. You're getting into oil!
油 浮油! 你要開進浮油堣F!
Keep coming.
繼續往下走
Plenty of room.
下面空間足夠
All right, below deck.
好了 到下面去
Abandon ship!
- 棄船! - 棄船!
Gibson! Leave it!
吉布森 快走
Below decks.
到艙塈a
Listen, we have to get as many of you on board as we can
我們得讓盡量多的人上船
before that oil catches fire.
不然浮油著火就全完了
You go below decks or you get off my boat. That's your choice.
你要麼挪進艙去 要麼就別待船上 自己選吧
Keep coming.
後面的跟上
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Careful! Careful down there!
小心! 小心! 別碰著他!
Careful! Careful down there!
He's dead, mate.
他死了 夥計
So be bloody careful with him.
那更不要動他!
Um, will he be okay?
他能挺過去麼?
The boy?
那個年輕人?
Yeah.
能的
He's coming back round.
飛機飛回來了
He's coming back round!
飛機飛回來了!
Come on, Farrier. Come on.
夥計 動作快點!
Get off the ship!
快跳船!
Come on, Farrier. Get around them.
加油! 再打下一架
Come on, come on.
加油!
Go.
快開船!
Go! Go! Go!
快! 快!
Go!
快! 快! 快!
Easy.
慢點
Take me home.
帶我回家吧
Where are you from?
你們是哪兒的?
Out of Dartmouth!
達特茅斯附近
Christ.
我的天
You from Deal?
從迪爾來的嗎?
I am!
是的
You watch the current at the mouth!
小心出口的水流!
Aye.
好的
And thank you!
謝謝你們!
That's a fighter.
有架敵機
Yes, an Me 109.
嗯 一架ME-109 從南邊飛來了
From the south. Peter, you take the tiller.
彼得 你來掌舵
Listen for my instructions.
聽我指令
Point her south!
往南開
Full speed, Peter.
全速前進 彼得
Keep coming round.
它一直在盤旋
Keep coming.
要飛過來了
Before he fires, he's gotta drop his nose. I'll give you the signal.
它開火前肯定會降低高度 等我信號
- Now? - No, no. Wait.
- 現在嗎? - 不不 再等等 ...
Wait for him to commit to his line.
等它開始瞄準了 ...
Now!
就現在!
He's gone.
飛機墜毀了
Yeah, bigger fish to fry.
是啊 掉海媮魚了
How'd you know that stuff, anyway?
你又怎麼知道這些的?
My son's one of you lot.
我兒子也是空軍
I knew he'd see us through.
我知道他會保佑咱們的
You're RAF?
你是皇家空軍的?
No. Not me.
不 不是我
My brother. He flew Hurricanes.
是我兄弟 還開過飛機橫穿颶風呢
Died third week into the war.
開戰第三周就犧牲了
No, stay downstairs, please.
麻煩待著 不要走動
We just wanna see the cliffs.
我們只是想看看海崖
- Is it Dover? - No.
- 那是多佛港麼? - 不
That's Dorset.
那是多塞特港
But it's home.
終究是回家了
We let you all down, didn't we?
我們是不是讓你們失望了?
Christ, how many you got in there?
我的天 你這船上裝了多少人?
Make your way to the trains.
走到火車上去
Where the hell were you?
大家參戰 你又在哪!
They know where you were.
他們知道你的壯舉
Bye.
再見
Cup of tea?
喝茶嗎?
喝杯茶嗎?
Well done. Well done.
幹得漂亮
Well done, lads.
幹得漂亮!
Well done. Well done, lads.
幹得漂亮 小伙子們
Well done.
幹得漂亮
All we did is survive.
我們只是勉強活下來了而已
That's enough.
這就夠了
Well done.
幹得漂亮
幹得漂亮!
That old bloke wouldn't even look us in the eye.
那老傢伙都不願正眼瞧咱們
Come on, private!
快過來吧 列兵
I know we're officers, but it's us or the enemy.
我知道軍官優先 但不是敵死就是我亡
So now is not the time to be particular.
不是講究這些時候
Well, Churchill got his 30,000.
已經撤回3萬人了
And then some.
那可不止
Almost 300,000.
快有30萬人了
So far.
到目前為止
So far?
目前為止?
I'm staying.
我要留下來
For the French.
等法軍
Hey!
嘿!
Where are we?
我們到哪兒了?!
Siding. You'll be pulling in in a minute.
臨時停靠 馬上就開車了
What station?
到哪一站?
Woking.
沃金站
Grab me one of them papers.
幫我拿份報紙吧
Go on!
快去啊!
敦刻爾克：三十三萬五千人獲救!
丘吉爾在眾議院發表關於敦刻爾克撤退的演講
Can't bear it.
我不忍心讀下去
You read it.
你念出來吧
Can't bear it?
不忍心?
They'll be spitting at us in the streets.
要是他們沒有鎖起門來等著淪陷
If they're not locked up waiting for the invasion.
那就肯定是到街上朝咱啐唾沫了
"Wars are not won by evacuations."
"戰爭從不是靠撤退取勝的"
I can't look.
我看不下去了
"But there was a victory inside this deliverance,"
"但應當注意到
"which should be noted."
這次救援卻孕育了勝利"
"Our thankfulness at the escape of our army"
"眾多盟軍士兵得以成功撤回 我們對此滿懷喜悅"
"must not blind us to the fact that what has happened"
"但不能因此 就對目前在法國和比利時的盟軍潰敗
"in France and Belgium is a colossal military disaster."
視而不見"
"We must expect another blow to be struck almost immediately."
"我們還須準備好 承受接踵而至的打擊 ..."
"We shall go on to the end."
"我們將戰鬥到底"
"We shall fight in France."
"我們將在法國領土上作戰"
"We shall fight on the seas and oceans."
"我們將在海洋中作戰 ..."
"本地男孩 喬治·米爾斯 年僅17歲 敦刻爾克的救人英雄"
"We shall fight with growing confidence and growing strength in the air."
"我們將以越來越大的信心和越來越強的力量在空中作戰 ..."
"We shall defend our island whatever the cost..."
"我們將不惜一切代價 保衛本土"
What?
什麼?!
"We shall defend our island whatever the cost may be."
"我們將不惜一切代價 保衛本土"
"We shall fight on the beaches."
"我們將在灘頭作戰"
"We shall fight on the landing grounds."
"我們將在敵人的登陸地作戰 ..."
"We shall fight in the fields and in the streets."
"我們將在田間作戰 在街頭作戰 ..."
"We shall fight in the hills."
"我們將在山區作戰 ..."
"We shall never surrender."
"決不投降 ..."
"And even if this island or a large part of it"
"即便全島或本土的大部淪為敵占
"were subjugated and staring,"
全體民眾飢寒交迫 ..."
"then our Empire beyond the seas, armed and guarded by the British Fleet,"
"我們海外的帝國子民們"
"would carry on the struggle"
"將在大英艦隊的武裝和保護下 繼續戰鬥 ..."
"until, in God's good time,"
"一直到天意注定之時 ..."
"the New World, with all its power and might,"
"新的世界 將挺身而出"
"steps forth to the rescue and the liberation of the old."
"傾其全力 拯救舊世界 解放舊世界"